Menaka

Structural Design Engineer

Tamil Nadu, India 91-79049 06148

https://www.linkedin.com/in/menakarf/

menakar84110@gmail.com

Motivated and passionate Civil Engineer with experience in SKILLS multifaceted background committed to providing top-notch services for clients utilizing my skills in design and engineering of buildings.

Mitek Sapphire **** Mitek Engineering 2020 ★★★★ STAAD.PRO *** AutoCAD **★★★☆** **** Plaxis 2D Autodesk Revit *** **** RAM Elements

LANGUAGES: English, Tamil

WORK EXPERIENCE

- Structural Design Engineer at R&K Building supplies, USA (via) QAE Consulting Private Ltd April 2020 – Present, Remote
 - Designing roof and floor trusses by creating a detailed truss layout in MiTek Sapphire.
 - Review and analyze architectural specifications and structural drawings.
 - Engineering components by ensuring that the work complies with customer instructions and by maintaining streamlined communication with seniors in case of discrepancies in plan.
 - Mastered in bidding 450+ quotes which includes residential custom homes, tract homes and commercial buildings as per IRC, IBC & ANSI TPI standards
 - Promoted as a team lead and hosted extensive training sessions for five new truss designers.
- Structural Design Engineer at K-I Lumber and building Materials, USA (via) QAE Consulting Pvt Ltd March 2019 – March 2020, Remote
 - Evaluated existing architectural and structural design plans to design roof trusses to fit the needs of the client and project.
 - Learned methodologies of lumber design, framed truss layout drawings and developed 3-D models using Mitek Sapphire and engineered trusses in integrated design software.
- Site Engineer at Kannan Construction Works

June 2018 – January 2019, Pudukkottai, TN

- Prepared structural & layout drawings using Auto CAD for residential buildings as per client requirements and practical considerations.
- Supervised and executed construction practices at site.
- Assistant Professor at Mount Zion College of Engineering and Technology June 2016 - March 2018, Pudukkottai, TN
 - Delivered course lecture, assisting and guiding academic projects, Student welfare counseling.
- Freelancer Experience in design of steel canopy as per ASCE-7 load standards.

EDUCATION

M.TECH -Structural Engineering 2014-2016

SASTRA University, Thanjavur

Scored 8.6 CGPA with Distinction

B.E- Civil Engineering 2010-2014

CARE School of Engineering, Trichy

8.44 CGPA, Anna university Rank holder